CHRISTOPHER POENARU

COMPUTER ENGINEER - FUNCTIONAL PROGRAMMER - TRIATHLETE - ROCK CLIMBER

SKILLS

Scala

Go

Haskell

lava

AWS + Heroku

Postgres

Redis

Cassandra

MongoDB

PROJECTS

SCRAVA

☑ KIAMBOGO/SCRAVA

 Community recognized, opensource Scala client for the Strava API

ROAD QUALITY

TRIFECTALABS/ROADQUALITY

- Crowdsourced road quality and traffic safety data for cyclists
- Allows cyclists to rate sections of a road or path to build a community driven topology of the safest cycling routes
- API and pathing logic implemented in Scala; custom mapping engine built with Rust

CONTACT



kiambogoagmail.com



chrispoenaru.com



chrispoenaru



kiambogo

ABOUT

Computer engineer with **5+ years experience designing, implementing**, and **owning** high-performance, **back-end** software and distributed systems. Cultivates a rich understanding of multiple layers of computer systems, from high-level applications and **database performance**, to **infrastructure**, **networking**, and **security**.

EXPERIENCE

MASONHUB

Los Angeles, CA (Remote)

SOFTWARE ENGINEER

Jan. 2019 - Jan. 2021

- Third engineer, responsible for designing, building, and owning multiple core systems that scaled the company from 0 clients to 35+ within 2 years
- Constructed Shopify integration, reducing technical client onboarding time to minutes
- Architected fault-tolerant, scalable printer management system allowing for custom supply chain documents. Successfully printed over 250,000+ documents
- Refactored critical, production database schema reducing average inventory ledger query times to 2.5ms and bulk order processing time to 160ms

HUDSON'S BAY COMPANY

New York, NY (Remote)

Aug. 2018 - Jan. 2019

- LEAD SOFTWARE ENGINEER
- Engineering lead of a team of 4 intermediate and senior level developers
- Directed team towards adopting a functional code base with Scala Cats + FS2
- · Architected a multi-service initiative to optimize safety stock levels and reduce order shorting

SOFTWARE ENGINEER II

Nov. 2017 - Aug. 201

 Conflated inventory management systems across banners as part of the shared selling initiative, driving double-digit growth for the Gilt banner

SOFTWARE ENGINEER

July 2016 - Nov. 2017

- Refactored mission critical service to use Postgres instead of Mongo; strategized deployment resulting in zero downtime
- Modified website delivery window calculation to include customer location, improving checkout conversion across many US states

STRAVA

San Francisco, CA Aug. 2015 - Dec. 2015

PLATFORM ENGINEER INTERN

· Optimized user characteristics processing with development of Scala service leveraging Spark

• Designed and deployed Spark cluster to production atop of Apache Mesos

EDUCATION

UNIVERSITY OF WATERLOO

Waterloo, Canada

BASC. COMPUTER ENGINEERING

2011-2016